Kyle Firstenberg

Full Stack Web Developer

kylefberg@me.com www.kylefirstenberg.com https://github.com/kylefberg

206-229-0643 Los Angeles

Technical Skills

Primary languages: JavaScript, Ruby, HTML, CSS

Libraries & Frameworks: jQuery, Node.js, Mongoose, Express.js, AngularJS, Rails

Build Tools: Bootstrap, Materialize **Database:** PostgreSQL, MongoDB

Other Related skills: Agile Development, Scrum, GitHub Bitbucket Workflow, Wireframing

Recent Projects

JoinIN Created a full CRUD app that allows users to create a playbook of personal plays. Users may add collaborators to both playbook and plays. Others may also contribute plays to playbooks. Users may call a huddle to meet in person. App operates on one platform, merging clients' offline and online networking needs.

Blontourage Helped client to develop vision of desired website appearance and features. Drew out wireframes and user stories for clarifying project. Used the Bands in Town API to feed real-time data to site. Met with client throughout project using the Agile Process.

Wander Created full CRUD app that utilizes photo collections from Flickr's API to create an album overlaid in Google Maps through their API image. Tracks where photos were taken and shows links to Flickr API and Google API. Acted as Scrum Master and developer, overseeing a team of four developers.

Riders Like Me Created full CRUD app that allows users to create a profile to share with other riders, listing riding experience, interests, and contact information. Users can connect with others by looking through other rider profiles and leaving comments on their pages or contacting them directly through their profile.

Professional Experience

		6 + 2016 B
JoinIN		Sept 2016 - Present
Web De	eveloper	Santa Monica, CA
	Built responsive multi-page user-facing website using HTML, CSS, SCSS, JavaScript	
	Collaborated with development team on both front-end and back-end using MEAN stack	
	Maintain and improve website for UX/UI	
	Designed mobile responsive website	
	Used Chrome Dev Tools to design and debug the application	
Web De	evelopment Immersive Student	May 2016 - July 2016
General Assembly		Los Angeles, CA
	Twelve-week intensive Web Development program taught full-stack web development in a	
	full-immersion environment.	
	Learned releant technologies, such as JavaScript, jQuery, MEAN stack, Ruby on Rails etc, as well a Programming practices, including Agile Development, Scrum, Trello, wireframing, Git, Github work to build websites, APIs and data-driven apps.	
Extra Sı	pace Storage	Nov 2014 - April 2016
Assistant Manager		Riverside, CA

Riverside,

Managed tenant database, updated files, and monitored for delinquencies

Property management of an 800-unit complex and tenant customer service

	Proactively showed people storage units and wrote leases	
Creativ	e DATE	Feb. 2009 - July 2014
Owner	/ CEO	Seattle, WA
	Drafted dating concept and built interactive dates in multiple cities	
	Networked with local business owners to establish discounts for users	
	Launched an LLC, as well as oversight of taxes and business model	
	Developed the website and internet presence	
Allstate	Insurance	Aug 2013 - June 2014
Senior (Customer Account Representative	Seattle, WA
	Created, managed, and updated insurance policies and database	
	Developed a network of brokers and business partners	
	Documented conversations with potential clients for follow up	
Grace P	oint Church	Sept. 2012 - July 2013
Operati	ons Director	Las Vegas, NV
	Developed volunteer base with leadership structure and coaching	-
	Organized backend database structure and usability	
	Recruited and increased volunteer base by 20%	
	Strategically developed 8% new volunteer leaders for key roles	
	Analyzed day-to-day operations and increased productivity of staff through clarity of roles	
	Developed job descriptions for staff along with performance expectations	
	Formulated and executed a new \$700k annual budget with monthly reporting and accountability	
Mars H	ill Church	July 2006 - Oct 2012
Executi	ve Pastor	Newport Beach, CA
	Coached, trained, and retained hundreds of high-quality, diverse leaders	•
	Implemented leadership tracking and development process	
	Organized hundreds of projects ranging from small events with 200 people to large events with we attendance	ll over 16,000 in
	Executed the launch of two new churches, resulting in growth to over 700 people	
	Coordinated volunteer leadership of a 3,500-person church	
	Formulated and handled general oversight of a \$1.3mm annual budget	
	Increased leadership recruiting by 100%	
Snohon	nish County Sheriff	July 2003 - Aug 2006
Deputy		Everett, WA
	Operated police software for query searches on suspects	•
	Wrote hundreds of reports as well as several search warrants	
	Conducted a swift water rescue of a stranded motorist, resulting in a merit award for bravery	
	Coached at-risk youth in shelters	
	Lectured students at public job fairs as part of recruiting efforts	
	Apprehended a wanted child molester with a \$5mm warrant	
	Conducted thousands of traffic stops resulting in arrests for drugs, guns, felony warrants, and DUI	

Education

General Assembly 2016

Web Development Immersive